David E. Ferro

Address: 11270 Apache Dr., Apt. 204 **Cell Phone**: (216) 258-6464

Parma Heights, OH 44130 Email: david-ferro@sbcglobal.net

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-ferro-979152172/

 ${\color{red} \textbf{Portfolio}:} \quad \underline{\textbf{https://davidferro91.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/index.html}}$

GitHub: https://github.com/davidferro91

Summary:

Full-stack Web Developer able to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript (with a focus in jQuery), and node.js to create a variety of webpages. Eleven years of logic-oriented and problem-solving experience from college coursework, teaching high school mathematics, and coding bootcamp. Detail-oriented, ensure projects are completed correctly, able to stay calm under pressure, and transform abstract, complicated topics into an understandable description.

Education:

October 2018 – April 2019

Case Western Coding Bootcamp

Cleveland, OH

- Full Stack Web Development
- Front End focuses: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query
- Back End focuses: Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL
- Utilizing GitHub and Heroku for hosting websites

August 2008 - May 2012

Case Western Reserve Univ.

Cleveland, OH

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude earning a Bachelor of Arts degree with a double major in Mathematics and Teacher Education
- Earned an A in the Java Programming course
- Received ETS Recognition of Excellence on the Praxis Mathematics Content Knowledge test
- Member of the Pi Mu Epsilon Mathematics Honors Society CWRU Chapter
- Studied in the Case Western Teaching Program in conjunction with John Carroll University to receive Ohio State Teaching Licensure at graduation

Work Experience:

August 2012 - Present

Horizon Science Academy

Cleveland, OH

High School Math Teacher

- Taught AP Calculus AB, Algebra II, Geometry, and Algebra I, Pre-Calculus, Trigonometry/ Differential Calculus, and Statistics
- Utilized technology in teaching, including Star Board, TI-84 calculators, document camera, and mathematics websites such as desmos.com and wolframalpha.com
- Served as 11th Grade Chair in 2013-2014, and 12th Grade Chair from 2014-2018
- Served as Master of Ceremonies for the graduations of the senior classes from 2016 to 2018 as well as on the Graduation Planning Committee
- Led multiple student organizations, such as Chess Club, Student Council, and Bowling Club

Aug. 2015 – Dec. 2017

Case Western Reserve Univ.

Cleveland, OH

Master Teacher/Adjunct Lecturer for CWRU Teacher Education Program

- Mentored teacher candidates in the CWRU Special Methods courses as they did observations, taught lessons (both mini-lessons and full-length lessons), and wrote reflective papers based on the classroom experience
- Met in monthly meetings with the teacher candidates, CWRU faculty, and Special Methods instructor in Reflective Triads where we discussed readings on teaching methods, techniques, and philosophy, as well as classroom observations and experiences, and the candidates' reflections

June 2012/13 - July 2012/13

Brush HS

South Euclid/Lyndhurst, OH

Summer School Teaching

- Taught two semesters' worth of material for remedial Algebra II students
- Led daily 2.5-hour lessons for the classes so that the students would be able to receive the proper number of hours in order to complete the program in a month

August 2011 - May 2012

Magnificat HS

Rocky River, OH

Pre-Student/Student Teaching

- Taught two AP Calculus AB classes and three Algebra I classes periodically from August through December and full-time from January through May
- Led a workshop during a faculty/staff in-service on creating presentations with the website Prezi
- Utilized Wikispaces and Smart Board technology within the classroom

Aug. 2010 – Dec. 2011

Case Western Reserve Univ.

Cleveland, OH

Calculus Supplemental Instructor

- Served as a supplemental instructor for Calculus I and II for Business, Economics, Life Sciences, and Social Sciences
- Led multiple weekly tutoring sessions and weekly recitation sessions
- Administered and graded tests and quizzes

References:

Contenza, Terri

Instructor

Department of Mathematics

Case Western Reserve University

Yost 330

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(216) 368-6678

Email: cxb10@case.edu

Davis, Denise

Director of Teacher Education

Case Western Reserve University

11635 Euclid Avenue

4th Floor – Room 417

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(216) 368-1505

Email: denise.k.davis@case.edu

Marencik, Joe

Faculty, Teacher Education

Case Western Reserve University

11635 Euclid Avenue

4th Floor

Cleveland, Ohio 44106

(440) 667-0593

Email: jjm203@case.edu

McKinley, Megan

Instructional Coordinator

Horizon Science Academy HS

6000 South Marginal Road

Cleveland, OH 44103

(216) 432-3660 x509

Email: mckinley@horizoncleveland.org

Nagelski, Denim

Math Department Head

Horizon Science Academy HS

6000 South Marginal Road

Cleveland, Ohio 44103

(216) 432-3660 x306

Email: nagelski@horizoncleveland.org